musopen.com 2014-02-13

# Privacy | Musopen

## Musopen’s Privacy Policy  

Effective Date: August 10, 2008

Welcome to the Musopen (“Musopen”) web site – [http://www.musopen.org](http://www.musopen.org/) – and any other services owned or operated by Musopen (the “Musopen Site”).  At Musopen, we strive to make your online experience with us secure and satisfying. This Privacy Policy describes and governs what information we gather from you, how we use that information, and what we do to protect it.  By using the Musopen Site (whether or not you are a registered member), you expressly consent to the information handling practices described in this Policy.  If you do not want information about you to be used in the manner set forth in this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Musopen Site.  

      This Privacy Policy is expressly incorporated into our **Terms of Use**.  Your use of the Musopen Site and any personal information you provide through the Musopen Site are subject to this Privacy Policy and the **Terms of Use,** at all times.    

 **Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy**      

      We may periodically revise this Privacy Policy.  Please revisit this page to stay current with any changes.  The most recent version of this Policy will always be available on the Musopen Site.  The effective date of any changes will be posted at the top of this page.  For changes to this Privacy Policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of personal information you have provided to us, we will attempt to obtain your consent before implementing the change.  Your continued use of the Musopen Site constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any future revisions.     

 **Information Musopen Collects**    

      Musopen collects two types of data about users:  (1) technical data automatically collected from all visitors (whether registered or non-registered) to the Musopen Site (“Automatically Collected Data”); and (2) information that you voluntarily submit to us (described below under “User-Supplied Information”).     

       **Automatically Collected Data** : The Musopen Site automatically logs non-personally identifiable information such as Internet Protocol address (“IP Address”), a unique user ID, the content and pages that you access on the Musopen Site and the dates and times that you visit the Musopen Site. In addition, if you come to the Musopen Site via a link from another site, we may also track the source of that link.    

>  **Information Regarding “Cookies”** :  Like many other websites, the Musopen Site may send one or more cookies – small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer.  Musopen may use cookies to track user traffic patterns as described above.  Musopen may use both session cookies and persistent cookies.  A session cookie disappears after you close your browser.  A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Musopen Site.  Persistent cookies can be removed. You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser, however, some features on the Musopen Site may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.  Please review your web browser “Help” file to modify your cookie settings. 

       **User-Supplied Information** :  In using the Musopen Site, for example when you register with us, if you donate music or money, or if you send us email, you will provide Musopen with data generally called “personally identifiable” information (such as your name, home/mobile telephone number or e-mail address). If you choose to provide such information, you are giving Musopen permission to use and store that information consistent with this policy.  Additionally, please know that when you register or sign in with Musopen, you are not anonymous to us.     

      In general, the types and amount of personally identifiable information we collect may vary depending on the activity.  Musopen endeavors to limit the collection of personally identifiable information to information we believe is minimally necessary to achieve our stated collection purposes.     

 **The Way Musopen Uses Information**    

      Musopen uses personally identifiable information to establish and enhance our relationship with you.  Musopen may use the information that you provide, or that we collect, to operate, maintain, enhance, and deliver the various features and services found on the Musopen Site (e.g., the Bid, Donate, Blog, and Forum features); as well as to track user-generated content and users to comply as a service provider with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act and other applicable laws.     

      Musopen uses all of the information that we collect from users to understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our users, to improve the way the Musopen Site works and looks, and to create new features and functionality.  Further, Musopen may use automatically collected data to: (a) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit Musopen; (b) monitor your participation in various sections of the Musopen Site; and (c) monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed.     

      We may use your e-mail address for administrative communications such as notifying you of major Musopen Site updates, for customer service purposes, and to send privacy or security-related notices.     

 **How Musopen May Disclose Information**    

      Musopen does not share your personally identifiable information with other organizations for their _marketing_ or _promotional_ uses.    

      We may share your personally identifiable information with companies that provide services to us, including outside vendors, contractors, or agents who help us manage our financial activities (e.g., for bidding and donation).  Such entities only use your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and for no other purpose than to provide us with necessary services.     

      Musopen may disclose personally identifiable information if required to do so by law or under the good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws (including, without limitation, U.S. copyright or trademark laws) or respond to a court order, subpoena, judicial or other governmental requirement or warrant in a manner required by the requesting entity.     

      Musopen also reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information that we believe, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to take precautions against liability; enforce our **Terms of Use** **;** protect Musopen from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; to initiate, render, bill and collect for amounts owed to Musopen; to investigate and defend ourselves against third-party claims or allegations; to assist government enforcement agencies; to protect the security or integrity of the Musopen Site; or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Musopen, our Users, or others.    

      In the event that Musopen is acquired by, merged with, or our assets are transferred to, another entity, such entity may be able to use your personal information under the terms of this Privacy Policy.   

 **Access to Your Personal Information**    

      If you register as a member of Musopen, you may update, correct, or delete your profile information and preferences at any time by e-mailing us at admin [at] musopen.com.  To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you account access or making corrections to your information.  You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.     

 **Children**    

      Musopen does not knowingly collect or retain personally identifiable information about persons under 13 years of age.  Any person who provides their personal information to Musopen ****through this website represents that they are 13 years of age or older.   If Musopen learns that personally identifiable information of persons under the age of 13 years has been collected on the Musopen Site without verifiable parental consent, then Musopen will take the appropriate steps to delete this information.     

If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has obtained a Musopen Site account, then you may alert Musopen at admin [at] musopen.com and request that Musopen delete that child’s personal information from its systems.     

 **Data Security**      

      Musopen uses commercially reasonable measures to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information.  However, no data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  We cannot, therefore, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Musopen, and you do so at your own risk.  Please know that although we make our best efforts to keep your information secure, this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.    

      If Musopen learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using this website or providing personal information to us you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of this website.  Musopen may post a notice on the Musopen Site if a security breach occurs.  Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.  To receive a free written notice of a security breach, or to opt out of receiving electronic notice you should notify us at admin [at] musopen.com.    

 **International Visitors**    

      The Musopen Site is hosted in the United States. If you visit the Musopen Site from the European Union or other regions of the world with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from laws of the United States, then please understand that you are transferring your personally identifiable information outside of those jurisdictions to the United States for the uses identified above in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  By providing your personally identifiable information on the Musopen Site you consent to that transfer.     

 **Third Parties**    

      Except as expressly provided otherwise, this document addresses only the use and disclosure of information that the Musopen Site collects from you or that you disclose to us. If you disclose your information to others besides Musopen different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. Musopen does not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others.  **  **    

 **Contact Information**    

      Please contact Musopen with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, your personal information, our third-party disclosure practices, or your consent choices by e-mail at admin [at] musopen.com or by mail at:     

 **Attention: Privacy Officer   **

Musopen    
5227 Shirley Ave.  
Tarzana, CA 91356
